settlement.org 2016-06-06

# Privacy Statement | Information Newcomers Can Trust | Settlement.Org

When you visit Settlement.Org it is important for you to know that your privacy is important to us. This page details the Ontario Council of Agencies Serving Immigrants', hereto referred to as "OCASI," policies on privacy-related matters.

## General Statement 

OCASI neither collects personal information about its users nor receives personally identifiable information about its users unless the user volunteers it. On occasion when users provide information to us (for example, email address) it is held in the strictest of confidence. If information is provided to us it is not shared with any outside organization or website (including government agencies related to the funding of Settlement.Org).

## Specific Examples 

### MySettlement.Org

This section of the website provides you the opportunity to participate in discussion forums, track your applications process timelines, track some elements of your site usage and customize site features. You create a username which identifies you in the discussion area and permits you to ask and respond to questions, and which allows you to share your timelines if you wish. We keep your information anonymous except for that information which you explicitly share using the MySettlement profile features. 

### Asking Questions and Providing Feedback 

In the Feedback page and comments areas of this site you are encouraged to send suggestions or comments to the Settlement.Org team. You are not required to include information about yourself unless you so desire. When you submit your feedback only the information you provide is sent to us. 

We encourage you to post your settlement questions in the [Discussion Forums](http://discuss.settlement.org/discuss/). We reserve the right to post and answer your questions in the discussion forums, if we believe that the information would help other newcomers. Your question will be edited to remove any personal information.

### Newsletter Subscriptions

When you subscribe to a Settlement.Org newsletter you need only supply an email address. This email address is used to deliver the newsletter to you. Your email is not used or known by any other newsletter subscriber, organization, website or government agency.

### Polls and Surveys

Occasionally Settlement.Org users will have the opportunity to respond to an online poll or survey. Your responses are private. We have no way of tracing them back to you. Feel safe in knowing that your responses are completely anonymous.

### "Cookies" - Statistics

A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the website may identify separate visitors to the site and track users' activities on the website. A cookie will not let a website know any personally identifiable information about you, such as your real name and address.

OCASI uses cookies only to keep track of how many people visit the Settlement.Org website and where they go on the site. Your individual movement cannot be tracked while on the site. Our only interest here is to be able to improve the quality of the site by identifying which parts of the site are not being utilized.

## Linked Websites

OCASI does not review the privacy policies of entities that link their websites to the Settlement.Org website. OCASI's policies relating to collection, use and disclosure of personal information as described in this Privacy Statement do not govern the activities of such linked parties in relation to users' personal information submitted via such linked websites. Users should review the privacy statements and policies of such entities prior to submitting personal information thereto. 

## Security

We have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information you provide. 

## Access to Personal Information

You have the right to request and obtain from OCASI the personal information OCASI has about you. If you have any such requests or questions about your privacy in relation to the Settlement.Org website please provide in writing to:

Dave Montague, Privacy Officer  
OCASI  
110 Eglinton Avenue West, Suite 200  
Toronto, Ontario M4R 1A3
